<conversation ID="Tammuz">
		<start ID="NewWelcome" IfHaveState="TammuzPermission" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz chimes a quiet tone.*}}				
			</text>			
		</start>

    <start ID="KilledTau" IfTestState="TauElse contains KilledByPlayer">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Tammuz is nearly silent but for a soft, shaky resonance*}}

        ...
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="Killed2">Tau is gone.</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Killed2">
      <text>
        You m-m-moon king. Madhand.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>

      <start ID="LostInSoft" IfHaveState="TauLostInSoft">
        <text>
          {{emote|*the chime rings shaky and loud*}}

          Wh-what is this? H-how is it meant? This outcome j-judders within and w-without us.
        </text>
        <choice GotoID="Lost2">Tau has departed.</choice>
      </start>

      <node ID="Lost2">
        <text>
          Wh-what will Tau b-be after soft? You, did, did you mean... wh-what c-could you say? Tau spins within, the g-gyre spins without.
        </text>
        <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
      </node>

    </node>
    <start ID="KilledCompanion" IfTestState="TauCompanion contains KilledByPlayer">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Tammuz chimes a querulous tone*}}

        O-oh. Elsefolder... th-this path you have l-laid upon Tau, it-it is best. It is good? P-please be good.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="Companion2">How does Tau's departure find you?</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Companion2">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Tammuz's chime rings even quieter and more tremulous*}}

        Un, un-uncertain. Tau l-leaves unfolded but the g-g-g-gyre yet s-spins. The s-spinning leaves me dizzy.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="PostQuestions">I have questions.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
    </node>

    <start ID="ElseWelcome" IfHaveState="ElseingComplete">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Tammuz rings a wavering chime*}}

        Y-you are here. Elseing h... hand.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="Else2">How does Tau's departure find you?</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Else2">
      <text>
        {{emote|*the chime is louder this time, but just as querulous*}}

        Sh-sh-she, th-this fate, it. It is a d-deep dark. Will Tau f-fold herself, I wonder?
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="PostQuestions">I have questions.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
    </node>



    <start ID="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz chimes a broad and booming tone.*}}

				You! Purpose-driven mad... madhand. You've come here, right? Then you must know power is our... the domain of being is one of power, wouldn't you say? W-Would you please agree with that?								
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Welcome2">...</choice>
		</start>
		<node ID="Choices">
      
			<choice GotoID="Name">I am =name=. Who are you?</choice>
			<choice IfTestState="GyredreamKnown" GotoID="Gyredream">Did you experience the gyredream?</choice>
			<choice IfHaveActiveQuest="If, Then, Else" GotoID="TauChime">I am to carry Tau's chime to Taproot, so she can leave Chavvah.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>

    <node ID="PostQuestions" Inherits="Choices">
      <text>
        If y-y, th-that... yes. Ask if, if asking.
      </text>
    </node>
    
		<node ID="Welcome2" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz quiets, then chimes in tottering, unsure tones.*}}

				You beast! You m-moon king! You... Our roars are beastial! Would you say so? 
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="What" Priority="1">This is all nonsense.</choice>			
		</node>
		<node ID="What" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The chime vibrates and shrinks its sound.*}}

				You- you don't understand? You... it's you. It's-
				
				It is as said: strange is the path to wisdom! Perhaps you will... perhaps it is you who must figure it out. Figure it all out..
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Unsure" Priority="1">You sound very unsure of yourself.</choice>			
		</node>
		<node ID="Unsure" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz makes a hollow peep.*}}				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Permission" Priority="1">Be uncertain, friend. You have my permission.</choice>			
		</node>
		<node ID="Permission">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz is silent and still.*}}
			</text>			
			<choice GotoID="End" SetIntState="TammuzPermission,1">I will give you a moment.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End" SetIntState="TammuzPermission,1">Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Name" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz chimes a small and bright noise.*}}
				
				Ta- Tammuz. Who becomes. Who is Twofirm even in -then.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Twofirm" Priority="1">Twofirm?</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Twofirm" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				The t-two sephirots. -then and -else. I cannot be -else. *I* cannot, of course. But -then? It does not seem so.
				  
				Their chimes ring at the right frequencies, others. But not so, mine.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Twofirm" Priority="1">Twofirm?</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Gyredream" Inherits="Choices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Tammuz quivers and chimes a jarring tone.*}}

				O-Oh. Oh u-uh oh oh. By contrasts, a q-quake stills even the most anxious trembling...
				
				The world... the world becomes and unbecomes. All the nervous, volcanic energy of being. Who becomes who? Three became one, but what of them now? 
				
				And w-what becomes of Tau? Of me? Of y-you?
			</text>
		</node>				
		<node ID="TauChime">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The chime knells a soft and brittle tone.*}}

				B-bright, she. And sang to the spark in T-Tammuz, too. By her, and through her, one could well-night feel full and at crown's end.

        She r-returns to Soft now, yes? And then to walk free as -else. See... see her there for me. G-Goodbye.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</node>
	</conversation>

	