<conversation ID="TauCompanion">
		<start ID="Welcome" IfTestState="TauElse contains KilledByPlayer">
			<text>
				Begone from me, stardimmer. Your own hand has vaporized your purpose.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</start>
		<start ID="Welcome" IfHaveState="ElseingComplete">
			<text>
				You thrived at the performance of a pruning motion, utensil. Now store yourself until Fate reshapes you.
				
				The end.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</start>
		<start ID="WelcomeHub" IfHaveQuest="If, Then, Else" IfNotFinishedQuestStep="If, Then, Else~Reunite Tau with Her Chime">
			<text>
				The utensil arrives. You, to prune the fate-rhizome and free our girl. Go now and perform the motion.
			</text>
			<choice Target="Seeker">You're a seeker of the Sightless Way?</choice>
			<choice Target="Taking">Where are you taking Tau?</choice>			
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</start>
		<start ID="Welcome" IfHaveQuest="If, Then, Else" Inherits="WelcomeHub">
			<text>
				Give her your parting words, utensil. Our hearts are in elsewhere.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</start>
		<start ID="Welcome">
			<text>
				Begone. Fate has not yet shaped you, utensil.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</start>

		<node ID="Seeker" Inherits="WelcomeHub">
			<text>
				Utensil? That is my avocation, yes. A million sun-dead homes I've roved, a trillion more await. I'm a worm in the loam of a cosmic wood, perched on a cosmic gulf, swathed in the god-manifold.
			</text>			
		</node>

		<node ID="Taking" Inherits="WelcomeHub">
			<text>
				Prune! The utensil prunes! -but no, the utensil quivers in uncertainty and vibrates out a question?

				The self is riddled with category errors. The thinking brain mistakes formation for meaning.
			</text>
			<choice Target="Understand" Priority="1">Tell me. I wish to understand.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Understand" Inherits="WelcomeHub">
			<text>
				Maggot! What do you think words are? Arrows of inquiry? Words are bricks. Each spoken is laid in bond and builds your prison. There is no understanding.
			</text>
			<choice Target="Throw" Priority="1">Bricks can be thrown, too.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Throw">
			<text>
				You tarry on the future's boundary with abandon, utensil. Throw your brick if you dare.
			</text>
			<choice Target="End">...</choice>
		</node>
		
	</conversation>

	