<conversation ID="Kah">

    <node ID="Start" IfHaveState="ChoseKah">
      <text>
        =ifplayerplural:May ye:Mayst thou= loose the bonds that keep =ifplayerplural:ye:thee= from =ifplayerplural:your:thy= goals, =factionaddress:Mopango=. Be free.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and be free, Kah.</choice>
    </node>

    <node ID="Start">
      <text>
        {{emote|*The creature-silhouette lacks any means to make sound, save for the pointed tips of its six flexible legs. These tap against the ground like a sparse but heavy rainfall on a scrap metal roof as the strange pseudo-beast skitters away from predicted or perceived threats.*}}
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="ConfirmRepairKah" IfHaveBlueprint="Repulsive Device">I offer you this repulsive device, unique one.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and... do as you please.</choice>
    </node>

    <node ID="ConfirmRepairKah">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Kah skitters away, but soon returns, and skitters away a shorter distance. Whether because of your words or because you are still, its desire for flight ebbs over the course of a minute until its escape attempts halt.*}}
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="RepairKah" RemoveItem="Repulsive Device" CallScript="XRL.World.ZoneBuilders.ChildrenOfTheTombQuestHandler.ChooseKah">Here. Take it.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">I am not yet ready. I may return.</choice>
    </node>

    <node ID="RepairKah">
      <text>
        {{emote|*You offer the repulsive device. As it nears the shining, dark surface of Kah's hide, a sudden fervor seizes the device, and it twists itself free, latching onto the entity with the hooked teeth of its mouthlike appendage. Kah scrabbles to escape again, but its limbs twist and collapse, rubbery and useless. Kah flails for a few moments before going completely limp*}}

        {{emote|*For a time, it is still. When it once again moves to clamber to the points of its shaky legs, Kah speaks in a smooth, buzzing voice:*}}

        I feel... calm.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="KahResponds">Are you all right?</choice>
    </node>

    <node ID="KahResponds">
      <text>
        I am weary to my core, but at last this once-hateful body obeyeth me. I thank =ifplayerplural:ye:thee= for restoring my autonomy.

        Memory of my once-self doth elude me, but I recognize the irony of my punishment. Once a strider, then sentenced to stride without restraint, forever. I knew only fear and flight. No more.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="KahFuture">What will you do now?</choice>
    </node>

    <node ID="KahFuture">
      <text>
        I shall enjoy my free mobility freely, for a time. After that, I know not. I may speak to these mopango creatures that named me, and find a purpose with them. I cannot ever repay their care, but perhaps I may repay =ifplayerplural:yours:thine=.

        I wouldst fain offer =ifplayerplural:ye:thee= a fragment of this form come loose. =ifplayerplural:May ye:Mayst thou= ever run free.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="End" GiveItem="Kah's Loop" IfHaveQuest="Fraying Favorites" FinishQuest="Fraying Favorites">Live and remain free, Kah.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End" GiveItem="Kah's Loop" IfNotHaveQuest="Fraying Favorites" CallScript="XRL.World.ZoneBuilders.ChildrenOfTheTombQuestHandler.FinishFrayingFavorites">Live and remain free, Kah.</choice>
    </node>
  </conversation>

  
