<conversation ID="Miryam">
    
    <start ID="KilledTau" IfTestState="TauElse contains KilledByPlayer">
      <text>Strange creatures can be so cruel and arbitrary, I say in greeting.</text>
      <choice GotoID="Killed2">Tau has departed.</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Killed2">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Miryam chimes low.*}}

        I cannot properly remember her with you here.

        Leave, I beg you.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>

		<start ID="LostInSoft" IfHaveState="TauLostInSoft">
      <text>I see you.</text>
      <choice GotoID="Lost2">Tau has departed.</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Lost2">
      <text>
        I do not know how to remember beloved Tau, struggling like a minnow in Soft. In a place between death and living.

        Leave me, please.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
    </node>
    
    <start ID="KilledCompanion" IfTestState="TauCompanion contains KilledByPlayer">
      <text>
        No parting is simple. I see you, -elser.</text>
      <choice GotoID="Companion2">Tau has completed the -elseing ritual.</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Companion2">
      <text>
        And the sole tether she reached for severed. I mourn for the future she built for herself, now, and worry for Tau herself.

        Thank you, all the same, for taking part in this. May you find your comfort.</text>
      <choice GotoID="PostQuestions">You are welcome. I yet have questions.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
    </node>

    <start ID="ElseWelcome" IfHaveState="ElseingComplete">
      <text>No parting is simple. I see you, fair -elser.</text>
      <choice GotoID="Else2">Tau has completed the -elseing ritual.</choice>
    </start>

    <node ID="Else2">
      <text>
        {{emote|*Miryam tolls.*}}

        And the gyre tide carries her a darkling way, perhaps never for us to see again. I will carry with me memory of her -then.

        Thank you for taking part in this. May you find your comfort.
      </text>
      <choice GotoID="PostQuestions">You are welcome. I yet have questions.</choice>
      <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
    </node>
    
    
		<start ID="Welcome">
			<text>
				Oh? A traveler? I see you, then. Live... and drink.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Name">I am =name=. Who are you?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Black">Your chime is cracked and ribboned on inside with starless clouds. Why?</choice>
			<choice IfTestState="GyredreamKnown" GotoID="Gyredream">Were you affected by gyredream?</choice>
			<choice IfHaveActiveQuest="If, Then, Else" GotoID="TauChime">I am to carry Tau's chime to Taproot, so she can leave Chavvah.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>
		</start>

    <node ID="PostQuestions" Inherits="Welcome">
      <text>Oh? Please, then, friend, ask.</text>
    </node>
    
		<node ID="Name" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in deep tones.*}}
				
				I am Miryam, friend.
			</text>			
		</node>
		<node ID="Black" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in long tones.*}}

				It's the kriah, traveler. I am in mourning, and I chime in low tones.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Loss" Priority="1">I am sorry, Miryam. Did you lose someone close to you?</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Loss">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in deep tones.*}}

				I swim in cool and dark waters, traveler. For me, it is Shiva, the lament of seven thousand years.

				I mourn the passing of all life, and all the necessity of death life must bring. For you, traveler, to come here, how many had to die? I mourn them.

				Or are you the rarest one, who walks below the bright arches and claims no such cost? Even then, what losses did {{M|you}} suffer to come, traveler? What selves of yours had you to shed? Those are -else to us, and I mourn them as well.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Loss2">*continue listening*</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Loss2">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in aching tones.*}}

				...but, too, someone close. Tau. Bright tau. She is gone.				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Gyredream">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in woeful tones.*}}

				Oh? You know of our pain. Our felt dream?

				The aching, traveler. =name=, I feel the slump of a Great Dying, the spinning out of all life on Earth, and I, drowning in grief. Or... do I? Is it but a new spring flowering, the slump having landed us in a meadow, and they, the gods, who are dead?	
		 </text>
			<choice GotoID="Aching">*continue listening*</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="Aching">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in aching tones.*}}				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">...</choice>
		</node>
		<node ID="TauChime" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Miryam chimes in melodic tones.*}}

				Oh? You would finish the -elseing act?
				
				I am your debtor, =name=. The ritual is how we organize the anguished practice of being. Now my grieving can begin.
				
				Bright Tau shines always, here or there.
			</text>
		</node>
	</conversation>

	
